{
    "id": "dbd39d2a99cf4816b0b26512c7436e71",
    "title": "Determiners Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Has she got …………… friends?",
            "description": "Any is a Group B determiner. Group B determiners can be used directly before nouns without of.",
            "answers": [
                "any",
                "any of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………….. children love stories.",
            "description": "Most is a Group B determiner. Group B determiners can be used directly before nouns without of.",
            "answers": [
                "Most",
                "Most of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………….. the shops are closed on Sundays.",
            "description": "We use ‘most of’ before a noun with an article, possessive or demonstrative.",
            "answers": [
                "Most",
                "Most of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………. philosophy is concerned with life after death.",
            "description": "We use much of before place names and nouns that refer to a subject or activity.",
            "answers": [
                "Much",
                "Much of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………. these blouses is loose for me.",
            "description": "We need ‘of’ before a noun with a determiner. However, we cannot use every before of. We use every one.",
            "answers": [
                "Every of",
                "Every",
                "Every one of"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "…………. my friends smoke or drink.",
            "description": "We cannot use ‘no’ before ‘of’. Instead we use none.",
            "answers": [
                "No",
                "No of",
                "None of"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "…………….. his ideas are too complicated for me to understand.",
            "description": "Before a noun with a determiner, all and all of can both be used.",
            "answers": [
                "All",
                "All of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I have invited …………… them to my party.",
            "description": "Before a pronoun we use all of.",
            "answers": [
                "all",
                "all of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………. these keys opens the door.",
            "description": "We need ‘of’ before a noun with a determiner.",
            "answers": [
                "Neither",
                "Neither of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………… my parents like traveling.",
            "description": "Before a noun with a determiner both and both of can both be used.",
            "answers": [
                "Both",
                "Both of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Janet earns …………… money in my family.",
            "description": "The most is the superlative of much. Most is used without of before a noun with no determiner.",
            "answers": [
                "most",
                "the most",
                "the most of"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You may take ……………… these shirts.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "either",
                "either of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}